- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- * Ohh...
- * 哦...
* Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? *
*谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ *
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he *
- * 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * If nautical nonsense
be something you wish *
- *如果航海废话
成为你所希望的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish *
- * 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通 *
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
*
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[both munching]
[两人都在咀嚼]
both: Mmm!
两人：嗯！
- [slurping]
- [发出声音]
- [chomps]
- [咀嚼]
- [slurps, yelps]
- [啜饮声，尖叫声]
- [slurping]
- [发出声音]
- [sniffs]
- [嗅嗅]
Ooh!
哦！
[moaning]
[呻吟]
[munching]
[咀嚼]
- Excuse me!
- 打扰一下！
Who, may I ask,
cooked this patty?
请问谁，
煮这个肉饼吗？
all: SpongeBob Squarepants!
所有：海绵宝宝！
- Did somebody
call my name?
- 有人吗
叫我的名字？
- Is there a problem
with your sandwich, sir?
- 有问题吗
先生，还有你的三明治吗？
- Yes!
- 是的！
I feel like I could die...
我感觉我快要死了...
[both gasp]
[两人都喘气]
And go to heaven.
并去天堂。
[both sigh]
[两人叹气]
- [thuds, smooches]
- [重击声，吻声]
- Oh, please, sir.
- 噢，拜托，先生。
Don't.
Stop.
不。
停止。
You really can stop, sir.
- [chuckles]
你真的可以停下来，先生。
- [轻笑]
Everyone seems to really
like the Krabby Patty.
大家似乎真的
就像蟹黄饼一样。
- Some people
started calling it
- 有些人
开始称呼它
the "SpongeBob Patty."
“海绵宝宝帕蒂”。
- What?
That's ridiculous.
- 什么？
这太荒谬了。
It's always been
The Krabby Patty.
一直都是
蟹肉饼。
- One SpongeBob Patty,
please.
- 一个海绵宝宝帕蒂，
请。
- Huh?
- 啊？
- Maybe you should
change the name of this place
- 也许你应该
更改此地点的名称
from the Krusty Krab
to SpongeBob's Place.
来自蟹堡王
到海绵宝宝的地方。
[explosion]
Ha, ha, ha!
[爆炸]
哈哈哈！
- Hey, that's a great idea!
- 嘿，这是个好主意！
SpongeBob's Place!
海绵宝宝的地方！
customers: SpongeBob's Place!
顾客：海绵宝宝的地方！
SpongeBob's Place!
海绵宝宝的地方！
- Oh, no, no, no, no, no!
- 哦，不，不，不，不，不！
Krusty Krab!
蟹堡王！
[whimpers]
[呜咽]
- Come on, guys!
- 来吧，伙计们！
Krusty Krab!
蟹堡王！
customers: SpongeBob's Place!
顾客：海绵宝宝的地方！
SpongeBob's Place!
海绵宝宝的地方！
- Help!
- SpongeBob's Place!
- 帮助！
- 海绵宝宝的地方！
- Admit it.
- 承认吧。
Without SpongeBob,
you'd be nothing.
没有海绵宝宝，
你就什么都不是了。
- Well, that's not true.
- 嗯，那不是真的。
I'm the one who created
the SpongeBob Pa--
我是创造者
海绵宝宝爸爸——
I mean, the Krabby Patty!
我是说，蟹肉饼！
customers: * Let's all go
to SpongeBob's Place *
顾客：*我们都走吧
到海绵宝宝的地方 *
*SpongeBob's Place,
SpongeBob's Place *
*海绵宝宝的地方，
海绵宝宝的地方 *
- [grumbles]
- [抱怨]
- Whoa!
- 哇！
- [chuckles]
- [轻笑]
- All right, Mr. Krabs.
- 好吧，蟹老板。
If you think
the Krusty Krab is haunted
如果你认为
蟹堡王闹鬼
and needs ghostbusting,
并且需要捉鬼，
I'll stay away
for a while.
我会远离
有一段时间了。
- Haunted, eh?
- 闹鬼，是吗？
- Don't you believe
in ghosts?
-你不相信吗
在鬼魂中？
- Oh, admit it!
——哦，承认吧！
You're jealous
of SpongeBob!
你嫉妒了
海绵宝宝！
- Of course not!
- 当然不是！
But I'll be cooking
但我会做饭
the Krabby Patties
from now on.
蟹肉饼
从现在开始。
Krabby Patties.
蟹肉饼。
Named after me,
以我的名字命名，
Mr. Krabby!
克拉比先生！
[loud crash]
Whoa!
[巨响]
哇！
Ouch.
哎哟。
- [sighs]
- [叹气]
What do we do now, Gary?
我们现在做什么，加里？
We've read every book
and played every game.
每本书我们都读过
并参加了每场比赛。
Hey, I know!
嘿，我知道！
How about another makeover?
再来一次改造怎么样？
- [yowls]
- [嚎叫]
- You know, I can't go
to the Krusty Krab.
- 你知道，我不能走
到蟹堡王。
But I can play Krusty Krab!
但我可以玩蟹堡王！
- [yowling]
- [嚎叫]
- Oh!
This can be the register boat.
- 哦！
这可以是登记船。
And you can be Squidward.
你也可以成为章鱼哥。
[squishing]
Ooh-whoo!
[压扁]
噢噢噢！
[squishing]
Ooh-whoo!
[压扁]
噢噢噢！
[stretching]
Yoink!
[伸展]
哟哟！
- [Squidward-like meow]
- [章鱼哥般的喵喵声]
- What's that, Squidward?
- 那是什么，章鱼哥？
30 Krabby Patties?
30 个蟹黄饼？
Coming right up!
马上就来了！
- Meow meow.
- 喵喵。
[jubilant music]
[欢快的音乐]
- [humming happily]
- [高兴地哼哼]
[metallic shing, knives chop]
[金属盛，刀砍]
[humming happily]
[高兴地哼哼]
[meat sizzling]
[肉滋滋作响]
[humming happily]
[高兴地哼哼]
*
Okay, everybody, order up!
好啦，大家赶紧下单吧！
Hmm.
唔。
Guess I'm used to cooking
Krabby Patties
我想我已经习惯做饭了
蟹肉饼
in mass quantities.
大量。
[sighs]
[叹气]
- [sniffing]
- [嗅嗅]
- Ooh!
- 哦！
- [sniffs]
Ooh!
- [嗅嗅]
哦！
[doorbell rings]
[门铃响]
- [slurping]
- [发出声音]
How's about making some more
多做一些怎么样
of those delicious patties?
那些美味的肉饼？
- I drew two more mouths
on my face
- 我又画了两张嘴
在我脸上
so I could eat
three at a time.
这样我就可以吃东西了
一次三个。
[munches, squishes]
[咀嚼，挤压]
- Okay, you guys.
- 好吧，你们。
Just make yourself
comfortable.
只要让自己
舒适。
More patties on the way!
更多肉饼正在路上！
[meat sizzling]
[肉滋滋作响]
[flames roar]
[火焰咆哮]
- Whoa!
- 哇！
- These are being sent back.
- 这些正在被退回。
[extinguisher hisses]
[灭火器嘶嘶声]
- [blows forcefully]
- [用力吹]
What?
What's wrong with them?
什么？
他们怎么了？
- Customers said
to make them good...
- 顾客说
为了让他们好...
like they used to be.
就像他们以前一样。
- Like they used to be?
- 就像他们以前那样吗？
It's the same formula!
这是同一个公式！
- Hey!
- 嘿！
I see the problem!
我看到问题了！
SpongeBob's not in the kitchen!
海绵宝宝不在厨房！
all: Huh?
全体：啊？
[all spitting and gagging]
[全部吐口水和作呕]
[all groaning]
- I don't think so.
[全都呻吟]
- 我不这么认为。
- I don't know why,
but it's bad.
- 我不知道为什么，
但这很糟糕。
- Let me out of this place.
- [gasps]
- 让我离开这个地方。
- [喘气]
Wait!
等待！
Please, don't go!
请不要走！
We're having a two-for-one sale.
我们正在进行买二送一的促销活动。
For every two you buy,
每买两件，
you can buy another one.
你可以再买一个。
[nervous chuckle]
Hold on, everybody!
[紧张的笑声]
大家坚持住！
I think I hear SpongeBob's
hideous laughter
我想我听到了海绵宝宝的声音
丑陋的笑声
coming from the kitchen!
从厨房传来！
I'll show you that the customers
are always wrong.
我将向您展示客户
总是错的。
- Oh, boy.
- 哦，男孩。
Huh?
啊？
- Now, go ahead.
- 现在，继续吧。
Call attention to me.
引起我的注意。
- Hey, everybody.
- 嘿，大家。
Look who's back in the kitchen.
看看谁回到了厨房。
- I'm ready!
I'm ready!
- 我准备好了！
我准备好了！
[mimics SpongeBob's laugh]
- That's SpongeBob?
[模仿海绵宝宝的笑声]
- 那是海绵宝宝？
Man, did he
let himself go!
伙计，他是吗？
放开自己吧！
- Who cares?
- 谁在乎？
I'll take a Krabby Patty!
我要吃蟹肉饼！
- I'll order some too!
- 我也订一些！
- Make mine a triple!
- 让我的变成三倍！
- Yeah!
- My appetite's back!
- 是的！
- 我的胃口恢复了！
[unenthusiastic munching]
[不热情地咀嚼]
- Mmm.
- 嗯。
- Yum.
- Is everybody enjoying
their Krabby Patties?
- 大家都喜欢吗
他们的蟹肉饼？
[mimics SpongeBob's laugh]
[模仿海绵宝宝的笑声]
- [moaning]
- [呻吟]
[lisping] Yes,
it's very nice.
[口齿不清] 是的，
非常好。
- [laughs]
- [笑]
It was me that cooked
those patties!
是我做饭的
那些肉饼！
You're all enjoying
my food!
你们都在享受
我的食物！
[customers spit]
【顾客吐口水】
- I thought
something was off.
- 我以为
出了什么问题。
[all groan]
[全都呻吟]
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
Oh, no, you don't!
哦，不，你不！
[loud crash]
[巨响]
[thuds]
[重击声]
[engine rumbling]
[发动机轰鸣]
[truck beeping]
[卡车嘟嘟声]
[lava gushing]
[熔岩喷涌]
[thuds]
Ha!
[重击声]
哈！
Anyone who
wants to leave
任何人
想离开
has to go
through me first.
必须走了
首先通过我。
[all chattering indistinctly]
[大家都在含糊不清地喋喋不休]
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
Ahh!
啊！
Ow!
Eee!
噢！
哎呀！
Hey!
Oh!
嘿！
哦！
Whoa!
Ah!
哇！
啊!
Blazes!
- G'night, boss!
火焰！
- 晚安，老板！
See you in the morning.
- Ow!
早上见。
- 噢！
Eee!
Hey!
哎呀！
嘿！
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
"SpongeBob's Place"?
《海绵宝宝的家》？
What in the ocean?
海里有什么？
Pardon me.
对不起。
Don't mind me!
别管我！
Just trying to
get in my own front door!
只是想
进我自己的前门！
[beeping tone]
[嘟嘟声]
- You've reached
the Health Department.
- 你已经达到了
卫生部门。
If you'd like to leave
a message, wait for the cough.
如果你想离开
一条消息，等咳。
[person coughs]
[人咳嗽]
- Everybody's a comedian.
- 每个人都是喜剧演员。
This is Squidward Tentacles,
这是章鱼哥的触手，
and I'd like to
lodge a complaint
我想
提出投诉
about my neighbor SpongeBob.
关于我的邻居海绵宝宝。
[siren wails]
[警报声]
- That should do it, Mr. Krabs.
- 应该可以了，蟹老板。
You'll be good as new
in no time.
你会焕然一新
很快。
- Wasting your time, boys.
- 浪费你们的时间，孩子们。
You should just take me
straight to the morgue.
你应该带我去
直接去太平间。
I'm done.
我受够了。
[faint laughter]
[微弱的笑声]
Stop!
Stop here!
停止！
停在这里！
[indistinct chatter
and laughter]
[隐隐约约的喋喋不休
和笑声]
[bell dings]
- Ah!
[铃声]
- 啊！
- [moans]
- [呻吟]
Make a hole!
挖个洞！
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
[whimpering]
[呜咽]
- [meows]
- [喵]
- Hey!
- 嘿！
- Oh, hello, Mr. Krabs.
-哦，你好，蟹老板。
Place your order with Gary,
please.
向加里下订单，
请。
And drop your money anywhere.
并将你的钱放在任何地方。
I'm running out of places
to put it.
我没地方了
把它说出来。
I don't even have time
to count it.
我什至没有时间
去数它。
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
[gasps]
[喘气]
[salt rattles]
[盐嘎嘎声]
- Here, try one.
- 来，尝试一下。
- [munches]
- [咀嚼]
Oh, it's delicious.
噢，真好吃。
- Sorry,
I ran out of napkins.
- 抱歉，
我的餐巾纸用完了。
You'll have to use
a $100 bill.
你必须使用
一张 100 美元的钞票。
- You deserve your own place.
- 你值得拥有自己的位置。
[blows nose]
[擤鼻子]
- Mr. Krabs, don't go!
- 蟹老板，别走！
I need you.
我需要你。
- Ah,
what do you need me for?
- 啊，
你需要我做什么？
You got everything:
你得到了一切：
a magic touch for cooking,
烹饪的魔力，
lots of customers,
很多顾客，
money.
钱。
- I could use a boss.
- 我可以找个老板。
Someone to
take all the credit
有人到
占据所有功劳
and all the money.
和所有的钱。
- Huh?
Hmm.
- 啊？
唔。
Well, I suppose
I could do some bossing.
嗯，我想
我可以做一些发号施令的事情。
How's 99% for me
and 1% for you?
我的99%怎么样
1%给你？
- Oh, that's
more than generous!
- 哦，那是
何止慷慨！
- [sighs]
- [叹气]
Oh, no people are ever
coming back here.
哦，从来没有人
回到这里。
Hey...
no people.
嘿...
没有人。
That's great!
那太棒了！
Because...
因为...
I hate people!
我讨厌人！
[laughs]
[笑]
* I hate people
*我讨厌别人
* People hate me
*人们讨厌我
* I prefer my own best company
* 我更喜欢自己最好的公司
* Single and secluded
* 单身且僻静
* On my own
* 靠我自己
* I can have the best of times
all alone *
*我可以享受最美好的时光
独自一人*
* Because I hate
*因为我讨厌
* People!
* 人们！
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
- [clears throat]
- Huh?
- [清喉咙]
- 啊？
- Are you the owner
of this food establishment?
- 你是业主吗
这家食品店的？
- Well, I do own
99% of SpongeBob's Place,
- 嗯，我确实拥有
99% 的海绵宝宝乐园，
so I guess that's a yes.
所以我想这是肯定的。
But you'll have to
stand in line
但你必须
排队
if you want to
place an order.
如果你想
下订单。
- Yeah, well,
I have an order for you.
- 是啊，好吧，
我有订单给你。
An order to
shut down your restaurant.
一项命令
关闭你的餐馆。
It's against
city health codes
这是反对
城市健康码
to sell food
in a pineapple.
卖食物
在一个菠萝里。
- [munching]
- [咀嚼]
Say, Andy,
you gotta try these patties.
说，安迪，
你一定要尝尝这些馅饼。
They're delicious.
它们很好吃。
[smacks]
[咂嘴]
- Carl, you're eating
contraband.
- 卡尔，你在吃东西
违禁品。
- You're not
the boss of me.
- 你不是
我的老板。
- Uh, yeah!
- 呃，是的！
I totally am
the boss of you!
我完全是
你的老大！
- Oh, what's going on?
- 哦，发生什么事了？
- We've been shut down.
- 我们已经被关闭了。
- Well, it was bun
while it lasted.
- 嗯，这是面包
当它持续的时候。
[laughs]
[笑]
- Meow!
- 喵！
- You know, I know of
an empty restaurant
- 你知道，我知道
空荡荡的餐厅
that's got
all its papers in order.
那有
所有文件均按顺序排列。
We can move in
right away.
我们可以搬进来
马上。
- Did you get rid of the ghost?
- 你把鬼魂赶走了吗？
- Yeah, the ghost is gone.
- 是的，鬼魂消失了。
- * I hate people,
I'm still that way *
- * 我讨厌别人，
我还是那样*
* La, la, la, la, la, la,
hey, hey, hey! *
* 啦，啦，啦，啦，啦，啦，
嘿嘿嘿！ *
- Sounds like
it's still haunted.
- 听起来像
它仍然闹鬼。
- * I hate SpongeBob
- * 我讨厌海绵宝宝
* I hate Krabs
*我讨厌螃蟹
* I wish they'd leave the ocean
in taxi cabs *
*我希望他们离开海洋
在出租车里 *
* And all the customers
can kiss my abs *
* 以及所有的顾客
可以亲吻我的腹肌*
* 'Cause I'm
the one and only-- *
*因为我是
唯一的——*
- Mr. Squidward!
- 章鱼哥先生！
- [gulps]
- [吞咽]
And...uh...
还有……呃……
oh...
哦...
[customers laugh]
[顾客笑]
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
- You know, I've been doing
some thinking.
- 你知道，我一直在做
一些思考。
You're a big part
of this place, boy-o,
你是一个很大的一部分
这个地方，男孩-o，
and I believe I should
share the name with you.
我相信我应该
与您分享这个名字。
Take a gander.
看看吧。
- I don't get it, Mr. Krabs.
- 我不明白，蟹老板。
It looks the same.
看起来是一样的。
- Well, climb up there!
- 好吧，爬到那里去！
Get a closer look.
仔细看看。
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
Where?
在哪里？
- Under the words "Krusty Krab."
- 在“Krusty Krab”字样下。
- "The Krusty Krab"...
- “蟹堡王”...
[gasps]
[喘气]
"And SpongeBob's Place."
“还有海绵宝宝的家。”
Oh, Mr. Krabs, you're the best!
噢，蟹老板，你是最棒的！
Whoo!
呼！
[thuds]
[重击声]
- [grumbles]
- [抱怨]